# ALINA BERNARDEZ



# FULL STACK DEVELOPER

#### CONTACT

1

654.564.992



bernardezalina@gmail.com



Alicante, Spain



https://alinabernardez.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alina-bernardez/

#### PROFILE

I was born in Germany and moved to Spain when I was only 11 years old. Looking for a creative path, I decided to study publicity in the University and then Pattern maker and fashion designer.

After 7 years of working in the textile sector, I decided that is was time to make a change in my life, and started studying computer programming, working hard to build a better outcome for myself.

I am a very committed, hard-working woman, and I'm determined to improve my skills every day and work as a developer in the future.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Full Stack mobile App developer | Product owner

**TILTIT** 

September 2023 - Now

- Complete full-stack development of an App that carries out a digital inclining test process for boats, through an inclinometer connected via Bluetooth.
- Play Store and App store upload

#### • FRONT-END:

- User interface development using Expo and React Native framework for Javascript, according to design indications.
- Understanding and developing funtionalities and calculations:
  - Log in and register (Formik and Yup)
  - Email and password verification
  - HTML and CSS static pages
  - Communication with the back-end (HTTP protocol handling with axios)
  - Dynamic line graph display using Victory Charts
  - Calculations for the inlcining test itself
  - Recieving data stream from Bluetooth device with RN Bluetooth Classic

#### BACK-END:

- o Node.js (Javascript) back-end server development using Express
- MongoDB connection and management using Mongoose
- o CRUD:
  - User registration, login and update (jsonwebtoken and bcrypt)
  - Project creation and update with different status and calculations
  - Email controller using **Nodemailer**
  - Automatic PDF, Word and Excel file creation with test results
  - File upload functionality with **Multer**

#### • HARDWARE:

- o ESP32 board and muRata inclinometer assembling
- o Arduino code update and upload
- o Bluetooth connection and data streaming testing

#### SHOPIFY:

- Shopify subscription management
- Content creation
- o Domain connection

# ALINA BERNARDEZ



# FULL STACK DEVELOPER

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Full Stack web developer

HYARKS September 2023 - Now

- Front-end development and design for a Company that works in the Renewable Energy Industry.
- User interface design using Figma
- User interface development using React framework for Javascript
- Developing web funtionalities:
  - Log in and register (Formik and Yup)
  - Email and password verification
  - o Real-time data display
- Back end with Node.js and Express
- MongoDb

# Freelance e-commerce developer

WASABI SOCKS December 2022 - March 2023

- E-commerce development using **Shopify** 
  - o Domain and Host purchase and transfer
  - $\circ \ \ \mathsf{Page} \ \mathsf{funtionalities} \ \mathsf{and} \ \mathsf{design}$

### Freelance Wordpress developer

MOODBOARD LADY May 2023 - July 2023

- Portfolio development page using Wordpress
  - Domain and Host purchase and transfer
  - Page funtionalities and design

#### EDUCATION

**THE BRIDGE** 2023 - 2024

Full Stack Developer - MERN Stack

MÓDULO SUPERIOR DAW 2021-2023

Desarrollo de aplicaciones web

FREE CODE CAMP 2022

MERN Stack

**OPEN BOOTCAMP** 2022 - 2023

HTML y CSS | JavaScript | React | Java

**DEGREE IN PUBLICITY AND MARKETING** 2007 - 2011

Universidad de Alicante

# ALINA BERNARDEZ



FULL STACK DEVELOPER

# SKILLS

#### Hard skills:

- Stack:
  - HTML & CSS
  - SASS & Bootstrap
  - Javascript
  - React, React Native & Expo
  - MongoDB
  - o SQL
- Wordpress
- Shopify
- Graphic design with Adobe
- Figma

### Soft skills:

- Proactive and problem solving
- Team player
- Good working under pressure
- Fast learner and resourceful

# LANGUAGES

# Spanish

Native language

#### German

Native language

## **English**

Advanced